cruiseweb.com 2019-01-10

# Privacy Policy | The Cruise Web

_The Cruise Web Privacy Policy was updated on May 25, 2018._

The Cruise Web (hereinafter, "us," "we," or "our") fully respects your privacy, therefore we've developed a Privacy Policy that explains how your personal information (as defined under applicable law) is collected, stored, used, shared and disclosed. This Privacy Policy only covers information collected through the use of The Cruise Web's Internet sites, applications and online services ("Services") and via direct communication between you and The Cruise Web, and does not cover any information collected at any other website, application or service. Usage of The Cruise Web Services constitutes your agreement with our Privacy Policy.

Our purpose in collecting your information is the same reason you provided it to us, to assist in booking travel. Travel services are almost impossible to obtain without information such as your name, address, phone number, other pertinent contact information and email address. To pay us, we need credit card information and the information required to process credit cards. We only use this information to serve you.

**Personal Information You Choose to Submit**

You submit and we collect personal information when you voluntarily visit our website, email or call us to enquire about or use our Services, submit comments to our blog, subscribe to email lists, enter sweepstakes or engage in The Cruise Web's other services. The information provided will only be used or shared with the cruise line and/or insurance carrier and/or other third parties in conjunction with your specific reservations or to fulfil The Cruise Web's business services, provide relevant products or for anti-fraud purposes.

The personal information that you submit and we collect includes your name, email address, telephone number, and other personal information that you voluntarily submit verbally or through text, checkbox, or via other data input while on our website. There are several areas on our website where you may provide personal information or will be required to register to obtain access to certain services not available to anonymous visitors. These include, but are not limited to: The Cruise Web's Personal Quote form, Email Deals or Newsletter signups, My Favorites and My Favorites Registration, Careers Applications and Contact Us forms. You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested, but, if you choose not to do so, in many cases we will not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to any queries you may have.

To make a booking through The Cruise Web, you must provide The Cruise Web with the following information: your full legal name, phone number, email address, mailing address, dates of birth, citizenship, and any other information required by the travel supplier to finalize your booking/reservation, plus any other special travel needs, dietary restrictions, or other information that you choose to share for your travel needs, all the above including for yourself and those traveling with you. By providing us with the information of any additional guests, passengers or third parties, you represent and warrant to us that you have the authority to do so on their behalf and have provided them with the information set out in this Privacy Policy. In addition to the contact information, you will need to provide your complete credit card information including cardholder name, card number, expiration date, CID number and billing address. To help prevent any fraudulent credit card use, if the credit card used to make a booking doesn't belong to any of the passengers travelling on that particular sailing, the credit card holder will be required to provide a copy of the credit card holder's government issued ID along with the copy of the credit card to assure the highest standard of fraud protection. 

If you are applying for employment or as a contractor with or of The Cruise Web, you will need to provide The Cruise Web with the following information collected through the online, in-person, or other method of job application: full legal name, social security number, citizenship visa and immigration status, address, telephone, email address, education history, employment history, and any other personal information you choose to share or that is required to process your application.

When you comment, post, submit or reply on The Cruise Web's blog, forum, social networking platform or other public medium, then your name (as submitted) and the comments, posts, replies or content you share may be visible to other users and may be read, collected or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to share or submit in these instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a social media comment, that information is public. Please take care when using these features.

**Information We Collect or Store Automatically**

We automatically collect certain types of usage information when you visit our website, receive The Cruise Web emails, or otherwise engage with us. For example, we use cookies to better understand our website usage information and to improve our website and your user experience. Some methods we use to collect this usage information are explained below:

_Cookies_ are small text files placed on your devices that uniquely identify your browser and enhance your navigation through the website. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use our website (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click, how frequently you access our website, and other actions you take on our website), and allow us to track your usage of our website over time.

_Website analytics_ include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, your geographical location data, information about your mobile device, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on our website, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

_Click-through URLs_ are utilized in some of our email messages, linking to content on The Cruise Web website. When you click one of these URLs, you will pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages.

_Phone calls may be recorded_ for The Cruise Web's internal training purposes, as permitted by law. If a phone call is recorded, all connected parties will be notified verbally, as required by law. We reserve the right to destroy this information pursuant to our own internal management policies.

**How We Use Your Personal Information**

The Cruise Web uses the data and personal information we collect for the purposes of consulting, quoting, booking, and servicing your vacations and reservations.

The Cruise Web also uses your data to identify and recognize you across multiple devices, provide and monitor the effectiveness of our website, monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, usage and demographic patterns on our website, diagnose or fix technology problems, and otherwise to plan for and enhance our services and website. Our goal in these cases is to make your experience with The Cruise Web more convenient and personal.

We use your credit card information to complete your purchase. For your convenience, we keep your credit card on file for billing and to facilitate any future transactions between us (e.g., additional or final payment, additional services and products).

We use your personal information to communicate with you and respond to your queries. We also use your email address, mailing address and phone number to provide you with details on current promotions, supplier notifications and any other communications required to insure you have a client experience consistent with The Cruise Web's standards and business philosophies. If you enter into a sweepstake, contest or similar promotion, we use the information you provide to administer those programs. If you don't want to receive email communications from The Cruise Web, you can opt out of promotional emails at any time by [_updating your preferences_.](http://choose.cruiseweb.com/email-preference-center/)

The Cruise Web uses tracking cookies to learn how visitors use our website. If you would prefer not to accept cookies, most browsers will allow you to make that choice: change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it; disable existing cookies; or set your browser to automatically reject cookies. Please note that doing so may negatively impact your experience using The Cruise Web's website.

We also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve The Cruise Web's Services and customer communications.

**Social Media Widgets**

The Cruise Web's website includes Social Media features, such as the ability to share content via Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, your email application or other Social Media Platforms. These Social Media widgets and/or features are owned by their respective third parties, and thus your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policies of those third-party companies, and not by The Cruise Web's Privacy Policy.

**Your Access to Your Information**

You have reasonable access your personal information held by The Cruise Web. To exercise this right, please contact us via telephone at **1-800-377-9383** (toll-free), **001-240-487-0155** (international), or email: [privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com). To update, correct, modify or delete your personal information at any time, contact us by email or telephone at the address and number provided above. To remove your email address from our email mailing list, or to modify your email preferences, simply follow the instructions on any promotional emails you receive or contact us at the email address or telephone number provided above. To remove your mailing address from our mailing list, contact us at the email address or telephone number provided above. We will act on your request promptly, after confirming your identity, and notify you within 30 days of the status of your request, but deletions or changes may take up to 60 days after the completion of an ongoing service, depending on the complexity of the request, before becoming effective. Please know that if you delete certain information, you may not be able to use our Services in the future without re-submitting such information. The Cruise Web will not delete any information required for maintaining accurate accounting and/or reservation records, and will not delete information required to be maintained by law. The Cruise Web retains your personal information indefinitely, as permitted by law, to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

**Sharing & Disclosing Information to Third Parties**

We share your information with the cruise line and/or insurance carrier and/or other third parties to perform certain activities in conjunction with your reservation and/or consultation. Examples of these third parties, and related services or activities include, but are not limited to:

  * Cruise lines, for processing and/or servicing cruise reservations and/or quotations
  * Insurance carriers, for providing insurance quotes and/or purchasing policies
  * Banks/payment service providers, for processing payments and anti-fraud practices
  * Postal services/couriers, for sending postal mail and managing subscriptions
  * Marketing service providers, for sending marketing communications and analyzing data
  * Shore excursion vendors, for providing shore excursions and/or quotations
  * Airlines, for processing and/or servicing airfare reservations and/or quotations
  * Hotels, for processing and/or servicing hotel reservations and/or quotations
  * Job application system, for company recruiting and hiring
  * Other suppliers, for processing and/or servicing other reservations and/or quotations

These third-party vendors and suppliers have access only to the personal information needed to perform their functions, but are not permitted to use it for other purposes. We expect our vendors, suppliers and other third parties to satisfy all legal and administrative requirements in respect to collection and storage of your personal information. However, we cannot assume responsibility for third parties. You may review the detailed privacy practices of those third parties on their respective websites. If you have questions or concerns regarding how your personal information is collected and processed by any of our vendors, suppliers and other third parties, or to request updates, corrections, modifications or deletions of this data, please contact the appropriate third party directly.

If you visit the "Already Booked" section on The Cruise Web's website, you will have access to links that, when clicked, will transfer you to different external websites which are not owned or operated by The Cruise Web. When leaving The Cruise Web's website to visit these external sites, you may be required by these third parties to provide personal information in order to finalize your booking. The Cruise Web's Privacy Policy does not apply to those sites; please review the privacy policy posted on those sites. The Cruise Web is not responsible for the content on those sites and therefore your use of such sites is at your own risk.

**Users Outside of the United States and Consent to Transfer**

The Cruise Web's Services are operated in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please be aware that information you provide to us may be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States or abroad. By using our Services or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States or abroad, in jurisdictions in which the privacy laws may differ from those in the country where you reside or are a citizen.

**Child Privacy**

The Cruise Web processes personal information about children when they are travelling with their legal guardians. We do not seek to collect personal information about children for any other purpose. If we have reason to believe that information is being provided by a person under the age of 18, we will not collect the information if it is not directly related to their travel with legal guardians. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 18, or equivalent minimum age depending on jurisdiction, outside the above circumstances, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible. If you believe that we have collected information from a person under 18, please contact us at [privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com).

**Security Procedures to Protect Information**

Security of personal information is extremely important to The Cruise Web and we have implemented commercially reasonable security measures to help protect your personal information. The Cruise Web employs physical, administrative and technical security measures designed to prevent unauthorized access to your personal information collected on and used by The Cruise Web at our website and when providing our Services. Our website uses SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) security technology to encrypt information you provide to us through the site. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its security. You use The Cruise Web's Services and provide us with information at your own initiative and risk. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of your personal information has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us using the details in the Contact Us section below.

**Inapplicability of Privacy Policies of Any Linked Sites or Other Parties**

The Cruise Web's website contains links to other sites such as our cruise line partners and other third parties. This Privacy Policy only addresses The Cruise Web's use and disclosure of your information as submitted verbally directly to The Cruise Web or collected on our website displaying this Privacy Policy. While we try to link only to sites that share our standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of our partners or any other third parties or the content of linked sites, although we do encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such parties or websites.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

The Cruise Web's reserves the right to change this policy from time to time, and if we do, we'll post any changes on this page. Any updated version of this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy, unless otherwise specified. If you continue to use The Cruise Web's Services after those changes are in effect (or such other act specified at that time), you agree to the revised privacy policy. If the changes are significant, we may provide more prominent notice or get your consent as required by law.

**Our Commitment to Your Privacy**

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to all of The Cruise Web's associates and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions, comments or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy, you can contact us via telephone at **1-800-377-9383** **(toll-free) or** **001-240-487-0155** **(international)** **,** or email: [privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com).

The Cruise Web, Inc.  
3901 Calverton Boulevard, Suite 350  
Calverton, MD 20705

Toll-Free: 1-800-377-9383  
International: 001-240-487-0155

Email: [privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cruiseweb.com)
